SIPHENATHI MKHOSI

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Siphenathi Mkhosi is a goal driven young woman, with good problem solving skills and a team player who is also comfortable working individually. I am computer literate and I have a passion for assisting my community with my skills. Further more I have more than THREE (3) years' experience working as a Tutor. Working as a tutor has helped me understand and master working with people and have good patience and deal well with different people. I am always prepared to put my knowledge and abilities to deliver the best results in everything that I do, while gaining immeasurable experience and skills to advance in my career pursuit. I am a self-motivated, goal orientated, driven and an individual who believes in lifting and empowering others through the knowledge that I have acquired, and experiences gained overtime.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Contact : 071 057 1638

E-mail address : siphemkhosi7@gmail.com Location : Cape Town, Western Cape

Nationality : South African EE : Black Female

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Competent in Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook, and SAP.
- Competent in Javascript, React, PSQL and Nodejs
- Good understanding of applicable laws, standards, and specifications.
- Excellent in budget control, management skills and managing critical skills.
- Research and data analysis skills and good in promoting participation for projects.
- Excellent Knowledge in ISO 9001: 2000 and ISO 17025.
- Great team player and can work well independently.
- Sales and Marketing
- General skills/ work

EXPERIENCE

[Tutor] Cape] [University of the Western [May 2019- October 2022]

Duties Include:

- Assisting the Facilitator during lectures.
- Helping students who are behind or struggling during and after lectures.
- Assisting with marking and portfolios.

[Tutor]

[Education Without Borders]

[March 2023- May2023]

Duties Include:

- Assisting the Learners with areas of study they are struggling with.
- Helping students who are behind or struggling with mathematics and english.

[Sales representative]

[Credito]

Duties Include:

- Advertising insurance, loans and credit cards inside pep store.
- Help new customers complete account applications, join insurance and apply for loans inside pep store.
- Help customers with queries and answer their questions.

EDUCATION /Qualification

Matric

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Graduate development programme award, 17 October 2018.
- UFH ARMSCOR Maths & Science Project achievement award, 19 October 2019.
- Computer Science and Information Technology Expo project award, 30 July 2016.

GOALS

- To become an excellent Web developer taking up challenging works in the Industrial structure with creative and diversified Projects and to be part of a Constructive and fast-Growing World.
- To make a position for myself in the competitive corporate world and contribute to achieving the goals on both professional and personal level.
- To work in an environment that challenges me to improve and constantly thrive for perfection in all the tasks allotted to me so that I can be able to showcase my coding and design skills.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Economic Strengthening and Livelihood Programme(work readiness) – Beulah Africa, April 2022.

- Interview skills.
- Financial literacy.
- · Communication skills.
- work readiness assessment.

Basic css, html and Javascript skills(frontend and backend courses)— Freecode camp and youtube, August2022.

- Javascript basics.
- Html basics.
- CSS basics.
- Nodejs.
- Postgresql

Links

- Github https://github.com/Siphemkhosi
- Personal Portfolio -

VOLUNTEER WORK

• Tennis Coach (Volunteer)— iThemba Labantu Lutheran Community Centre, March 2018— May 2018.

REFERENCES

• Available upon request

